<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Fitness, | Nick Bucciarelli]]></title>
  <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/categories/fitness/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-12T15:39:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Bucciarelli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2014 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/2014-in-review/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-12T14:47:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/2014-in-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sorry it&rsquo;s been a while, folks. I am not good at keeping up with a blog.</p>

<p>2014 has been a whirlwind of a year. If I had told you what was being planned by the beginning of the year, you guys would have told me I was f*cking crazy with no way of completing that list. I told myself the same thing at the beginning of the year.</p>

<p>I wanted to make 2014 special.</p>

<ul>
<li>Blog more</li>
<li>Get more involved in the community</li>
<li>Certain salary goals</li>
<li>Lose 40+ pounds and get fit</li>
<li>Get engaged</li>
<li>Lead by example</li>
</ul>


<p>There were a lot of flaws in my life that needed to be fixed.</p>

<h3>Blog more</h3>

<p>First, let&rsquo;s start with the negative. I fail at blogging often. Made a goal to blog at least once a week and failed miserably at doing so. Apologies! Let&rsquo;s hope I can keep up this year.</p>

<h3>Get more involved in the community</h3>

<p>While I was learning, there was an inherant issue with my involvement in the community. There needed to be more of it. I&rsquo;m not talking about going to every meetup under the sun, I wasn&rsquo;t participating at all. Going to anything at all would be an improvement. To a certain extent, this was fulfilled. Once a month, I would go to a meetup of interest with no agenda in mind. Just there to hang out!</p>

<h3>Certain salary goals</h3>

<p>A resolution/todo list wouldn&rsquo;t be complete without having some vain goals. Mine was to meet certain salary goals. Not only did I start a new job, I also pushed very hard on the consulting front to meet these expectations. It was extremely difficult and time consuming, but alas, they were met.</p>

<h3>Get fit</h3>

<p><img src="/images/2015-01-12-2014-in-review/exercise.jpg" title="&ldquo;Exercise&rdquo; &ldquo;Exercise&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Truth.</p>

<p>Another goal that is on EVERYONE&rsquo;s resolution list is to lose weight. My health was on the decline. Since moving to Charleston, I have been eating out entirely way too much and eating the wrong kinds of foods. It&rsquo;s been a goal of mine for the past few years and it&rsquo;s never been taken seriously. Until I stepped on the scale in early January, I didn&rsquo;t think anything of it. When I DID step on the scale, however, it was not a pretty sight. Something had to change. If you&rsquo;ve been following my blog, you know what&rsquo;s going on here.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2015-01-12-2014-in-review/results.png" title="&ldquo;Results&rdquo; &ldquo;Results&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Sick gains, yo.</p>

<h3>Get engaged</h3>

<p>This was my number one priority. I&rsquo;ve been dating a beautiful woman who deserves better then me. Getting engaged has been a long time coming. Frankly, it&rsquo;s taken too long. She stuck around.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2015-01-12-2014-in-review/engagement.jpg" title="&ldquo;Engagement&rdquo; &ldquo;Engagement&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>She said yes! Wooo!</p>

<h3>Lead by example</h3>

<p>Part of my reasoning for taking the new job at The Iron Yard was to lead by example. It was nice absorbing all I could learn; but I had to give a bit back. Whether it was via teaching people programming or teaching people how to work out. I wanted to be a motivation for people to better themselves!</p>

<p>All in all, 2014 was a crazy ass year. If 2015 is anything like it, I&rsquo;m in for a wild ride.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
