<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 26+ | Nick Bucciarelli]]></title>
  <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/categories/26-plus/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-22T21:31:53-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Bucciarelli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update - Week 2 and 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/09/22/progress-update-week-2-and-3/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-22T20:54:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/09/22/progress-update-week-2-and-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Week 2 Weigh In</h3>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a picture of me dying. I have the coolest t-shirts.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2014-09-22-progress-update-week-2-and-3/im_dying.jpg" title="&ldquo;I&rsquo;m dying&rdquo; &ldquo;I&rsquo;m dying&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Week 1 &ndash; Day 1: <strong>185.0</strong></p>

<p>Week 2 &ndash; Day 8: <strong>179.8</strong></p>

<p>Week 3 &ndash; Day 15: <strong>178.2</strong></p>

<p>Current total loss: <strong>6.8</strong></p>

<p>Last week, I did not lose much weight at all &ndash;<strong>1.6 pounds.</strong> Even though progress should not be as large as week 1, there still should have been more then that. There are several reason for this:</p>

<h4>No week should have the same progress as week 1</h4>

<h4>My diet needs to change</h4>

<p>I need to cut some of the carbs out of my diet. I&rsquo;m consuming a lot more then I should. Instead of having 1 cup of pasta/rice, it&rsquo;s being cut down to 2/3.</p>

<h4>I had a cheat day (A day to eat myself silly!)</h4>

<p>Ain&rsquo;t she purty!?
<img src="/images/2014-09-22-progress-update-week-2-and-3/me_and_jenny.jpg" title="&ldquo;Me and Jenny&rdquo; &ldquo;Me and Jenny&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Jenny&rsquo;s, Brian&rsquo;s, and Shannon&rsquo;s (Brian&rsquo;s lady) birthdays are all in September, so we had a big birthday bash on Saturday. I ate myself silly. Hot dogs, burgers, doughnuts, cake &ndash; so much sugar I made myself sick. This was for a reason. Even though this cheat day was planned, I wanted to stop all of these cravings I was having, so I ate the foods my body was craving until I got sick. And that&rsquo;s OK. Now, I ain&rsquo;t cravin' shit!</p>

<p>Cravings were not a huge problem the second week. I am on autopilot now.</p>

<hr>


<h3>Week 3 Weigh In</h3>

<p>Week 1 &ndash; Day 1: <strong>185.0</strong></p>

<p>Week 2 &ndash; Day 8: <strong>179.8</strong></p>

<p>Week 3 &ndash; Day 15: <strong>178.2</strong></p>

<p>Week 4 &ndash; Day 22: <strong>173.8</strong></p>

<p>Current total loss: <strong>11.2</strong></p>

<p>HUGE week!! <strong>4.4 pounds</strong> lost! Last week was ROUGH. My body is having trouble adjusting to the changes in diet and it&rsquo;s not taking it well. Kris Gethin warned this would happen, but it&rsquo;s hard to prepare for it. I&rsquo;m extremely irritable and can&rsquo;t focus as well as normal. The lack of fat sucks.</p>

<p>The irritability issues lasted a few days. No big deal. I&rsquo;m still having issues focusing like I used to, but it&rsquo;s getting better!</p>

<p>I also ran the &ldquo;Run or Dye&rdquo; 5k on September 20th! It was a ton of fun &ndash; everyone has bags of dye and runs a few miles while throwing the dye on other people. I was all kinds of green/yellow/purple/pink while going to the gym later for my 2nd cardio session.</p>

<p>Me and Brian posing at the start
<img src="/images/2014-09-22-progress-update-week-2-and-3/start.jpg" title="&ldquo;Me and Brian&rdquo; &ldquo;Me and Brian&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>I lost Brian.
<img src="/images/2014-09-22-progress-update-week-2-and-3/finish.jpg" title="&ldquo;Where did Brian go?&rdquo; &ldquo;Where did Brian go?&rdquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First VLog! Week 2 - Day 12]]></title>
    <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/09/22/my-first-vlog/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-22T20:41:42-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/09/22/my-first-vlog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lWZ4sgRFqoo"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/lWZ4sgRFqoo/0.jpg" alt="Week 2 - Day 12" /></a></p>

<p>I am not a good writer, nor am I good in front of a camera. So why not practice both by blogging more, and vlogging more? Day 12 of my body transformation is a decent place to start, eh?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week 1 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/09/08/week-1-in-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-08T12:06:26-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/09/08/week-1-in-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey guys, I&rsquo;m back to review my first week on my new workout/diet regimen. First, the progress:</p>

<p>Started program: <strong>185.0</strong></p>

<p>Current weight: <strong>179.8</strong></p>

<p><strong>5.2</strong> lbs lost. Hell yeah! The first week is always the biggest week as far as weight loss is concerned because your body is expelling all of the sugars and bad nutrients it stored from before the changes. I was already getting pretty lean to begin with, so that is a big loss for me so far!</p>

<p>The first couple of days were extremely rough &ndash; getting used to the supplements and eating every 2-3 hours. I had to figure out a way to make the food not be so bland so I have been putting hot sauce on EVERYTHING.</p>

<p>My body is taking to it pretty well, though. I find myself more clear-headed and with more energy due to eliminating most all sugar.</p>

<h3>Getting dommed(dominated) DOMS</h3>

<p>DOMS, or delayed onset muscle soreness, is an acronym a lot of people use to describe the sore muscles 2 days after you work out. The day after workout isn&rsquo;t usually too bad. The 2nd day after the workout is the worst. This is when your muscles turn really sore and you need to recover the muscles then most of all.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2014-09-08-week-1-in-review/motivation.jpeg" title="&lsquo;Motivation&rsquo; &lsquo;Motivation&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>Worst day</h3>

<p>Even though every day is kicking my ass and pushing my body to it&rsquo;s limits, the worst day was day 5 &ndash; shoulders, calves, and abs. The reason being is I haven&rsquo;t worked my calf muscles out in a very long time. I still can not walk due to soreness and it&rsquo;s been 3 days.</p>

<h3>Favorite day</h3>

<p>I really enjoyed yesterdays workout &ndash; Legs. We did some crazy high reps of a lot of weight to destroy your legs. Was a great and tiring workout.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.bodybuilding.com/fun/kris-gethin-12-week-daily-trainer-week-1-day-7.html">http://www.bodybuilding.com/fun/kris-gethin-12-week-daily-trainer-week-1-day-7.html</a></p>

<p><img src="/images/2014-09-08-week-1-in-review/before_legpress.jpeg" title="&lsquo;Before legpress&rsquo; &lsquo;Before legpress&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Before 150 reps on legpress. (Don&rsquo;t worry, I fixed my footing before I started!)</p>

<p><img src="/images/2014-09-08-week-1-in-review/after_legpress.jpeg" title="&lsquo;After legpress&rsquo; &lsquo;After legpress&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>After 150 reps on legpress.</p>

<h3>My first eating out experience</h3>

<p>Eating out when you are changing around your diet is a very difficult thing to do. We went to Moe&rsquo;s and I sacrificed a lot of things I would previously have added to my burrito&rsquo;s.</p>

<p>No dairy, soy, and as little sugar as possible. So, I had a whole grain tortilla, chicken, onions, cilantro, fresh jalapeno and that&rsquo;s it. It was surprisingly good, though! I also had to cut the portions to be fist-sized. So I ate half of the burrito first, then the other half 2.5 hours later.</p>

<h3>Tips</h3>

<h5>Get to sleep earlier</h5>

<p>I have to start going to bed earlier. I go to bed around 11:30pm and wind up laying awake for a few hours before sleeping. I need to shut down the electronics earlier and get to bed earlier. This is a lifestyle change, not just a workout/diet regimen.</p>

<h5>Fight the cravings</h5>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been pretty good about fighting the cravings so far. My advice is to fight through it. They will stop. After day 3, I haven&rsquo;t really had a craving to eat anything crazy. I&rsquo;m on autopilot now.</p>

<h5>Surround yourself with good people</h5>

<p>Surround yourself with people who motivate and inspire. Do not surround yourself with people who push you towards cheating. Just like in every aspect of life, if you surround yourself with people who support you, things will succeed so much more often.</p>

<h3>Cheat Days</h3>

<p>Cheat days are not advised. Once you fall back into 1 cheat day, it will turn into many. I have allotted myself 2 cheat days throughout the entirety of the program.</p>

<ul>
<li>Jenny&rsquo;s birthday is this weekend. I will be &ldquo;cheating&rdquo; on saturday by consuming some meats that are a bit more fatty then I would usually consume. Still no dairy, though. Lame. I miss cheese.</li>
<li>Thanksgiving. Turkey and corn. All I will eat, but I will consume a large quantity of said foods. Ain&rsquo;t no diet getting in the way of my Thanksgiving.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/09/01/day-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-01T11:15:46-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/09/01/day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.bodybuilding.com/fun/kris-gethin-12-week-daily-trainer-week-1-day-1.html">Day 1 &ndash; Legs</a></p>

<p>Here we go.</p>

<p>Starting weight: 185.0lbs.</p>

<p>I have done the breakfast meals (egg whites and oats) and did the cardio already (20 minutes of running). I am sweating profusely because I decided to take my dog for a run. Apparently she is way out of shape. So we&rsquo;re adding one more creature to the lifestyle mix: my dog. We ran 3.5 kilometers. She&rsquo;s slowin' me down!</p>

<p><img src="/images/2014-09-01-day-1/abby_tired.jpg" title="&lsquo;Abby is tired.&rsquo; &lsquo;Abby is tired.&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I was supposed to take before pictures, but I forgot. I will take those as soon as I cool down.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2014-09-01-day-1/after_run.jpg" title="&lsquo;After run&rsquo; &lsquo;After run&rsquo; class=&lsquo;day_1_after_run&rsquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building Better Habits.]]></title>
    <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/08/31/building-better-habits/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-31T21:57:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/08/31/building-better-habits</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have had the priveledge of being a part of a company that not only wants me to progress in my career, but personally as well. To do this, we put together 2 projects that do exactly that. 1 &ndash; do something, in short, that helps the company. 2 &ndash; do something that helps you personally. We are free to do whatever we want that falls within those broad scopes.</p>

<p>As some of you may know, Charleston can do quite a number to you. All of teh delicious food and bars makes for quite the unhealthy environment. I have regrettably gained a lot of weight since I have been here. I went from 170-180 pounds all of the way up to 220. I looked back at some of my habits and realized that I have become way to sedentary. Something needed to change. It was then that I went to the gym and got a personal trainer. He has since helped me lose 30 pounds and realize a love for exercising that I haven&rsquo;t known before.</p>

<p>Before the weight loss:</p>

<p><img src="/images/2014-08-31-building-better-habits/jenny_and_me.jpg" title="&lsquo;Before the weight loss. Jenny looks beautiful, as always!&rsquo; &lsquo;Before the weight loss. Jenny looks beautiful, as always!&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>After the weight loss:</p>

<p><img src="/images/2014-08-31-building-better-habits/after_weight_loss.jpg" title="&lsquo;After the weight loss&rsquo; &lsquo;After the weight loss&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Now, I am in better shape then I was in before (a WHOLE lot better), but there are still some goals that haven&rsquo;t been met quite yet. I am plateuing in my training and need a change. Jermaine (my trainer) has worked wonders and helped me thus far. I am taking it upon myself to take it to the next level. With my personal project, I&rsquo;ll be following a very regimented program &ndash; in both DIET and exercise.</p>

<p>Not only am I going to follow this regimen, two of my other friends are doing this with me. One to keep me accountable for every misstep and another to train and help better his habits as well.</p>

<p>DIET. MAN, DIET. I am not talking about eating salads every meal and cutting all kinds of calories. Your diet is what you eat on a day to day basis. My diet has been absolute shit and needs to change. The majority of body transformations aren&rsquo;t from exercise, they&rsquo;re from a strict diet of healthy foods.  In short, we are eating infinitely healthier &ndash; less for enjoyment and more for health.</p>

<p>Exercise &ndash; I am still keeping to a very strict exercise routine, just changing how often I work out. 2 days on, 1 day off.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.bodybuilding.com/fun/kris-gethin-12-week-daily-trainer.html">Kris Gethin &ndash; 12 Week Training</a></p>

<p>I am doing this routine and am going to love every minute of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
