<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Work | Nick Bucciarelli]]></title>
  <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/categories/work/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-12T15:39:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Bucciarelli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2014 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/2014-in-review/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-12T14:47:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/2014-in-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sorry it&rsquo;s been a while, folks. I am not good at keeping up with a blog.</p>

<p>2014 has been a whirlwind of a year. If I had told you what was being planned by the beginning of the year, you guys would have told me I was f*cking crazy with no way of completing that list. I told myself the same thing at the beginning of the year.</p>

<p>I wanted to make 2014 special.</p>

<ul>
<li>Blog more</li>
<li>Get more involved in the community</li>
<li>Certain salary goals</li>
<li>Lose 40+ pounds and get fit</li>
<li>Get engaged</li>
<li>Lead by example</li>
</ul>


<p>There were a lot of flaws in my life that needed to be fixed.</p>

<h3>Blog more</h3>

<p>First, let&rsquo;s start with the negative. I fail at blogging often. Made a goal to blog at least once a week and failed miserably at doing so. Apologies! Let&rsquo;s hope I can keep up this year.</p>

<h3>Get more involved in the community</h3>

<p>While I was learning, there was an inherant issue with my involvement in the community. There needed to be more of it. I&rsquo;m not talking about going to every meetup under the sun, I wasn&rsquo;t participating at all. Going to anything at all would be an improvement. To a certain extent, this was fulfilled. Once a month, I would go to a meetup of interest with no agenda in mind. Just there to hang out!</p>

<h3>Certain salary goals</h3>

<p>A resolution/todo list wouldn&rsquo;t be complete without having some vain goals. Mine was to meet certain salary goals. Not only did I start a new job, I also pushed very hard on the consulting front to meet these expectations. It was extremely difficult and time consuming, but alas, they were met.</p>

<h3>Get fit</h3>

<p><img src="/images/2015-01-12-2014-in-review/exercise.jpg" title="&ldquo;Exercise&rdquo; &ldquo;Exercise&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Truth.</p>

<p>Another goal that is on EVERYONE&rsquo;s resolution list is to lose weight. My health was on the decline. Since moving to Charleston, I have been eating out entirely way too much and eating the wrong kinds of foods. It&rsquo;s been a goal of mine for the past few years and it&rsquo;s never been taken seriously. Until I stepped on the scale in early January, I didn&rsquo;t think anything of it. When I DID step on the scale, however, it was not a pretty sight. Something had to change. If you&rsquo;ve been following my blog, you know what&rsquo;s going on here.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2015-01-12-2014-in-review/results.png" title="&ldquo;Results&rdquo; &ldquo;Results&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Sick gains, yo.</p>

<h3>Get engaged</h3>

<p>This was my number one priority. I&rsquo;ve been dating a beautiful woman who deserves better then me. Getting engaged has been a long time coming. Frankly, it&rsquo;s taken too long. She stuck around.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2015-01-12-2014-in-review/engagement.jpg" title="&ldquo;Engagement&rdquo; &ldquo;Engagement&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>She said yes! Wooo!</p>

<h3>Lead by example</h3>

<p>Part of my reasoning for taking the new job at The Iron Yard was to lead by example. It was nice absorbing all I could learn; but I had to give a bit back. Whether it was via teaching people programming or teaching people how to work out. I wanted to be a motivation for people to better themselves!</p>

<p>All in all, 2014 was a crazy ass year. If 2015 is anything like it, I&rsquo;m in for a wild ride.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update - the Weeks I've Missed.]]></title>
    <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/10/28/progress-update-the-weeks-ive-missed/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-28T13:26:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/10/28/progress-update-the-weeks-ive-missed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2014-10-28-progress-update-the-weeks-ive-missed/belt.jpg" title="&ldquo;Belt&rdquo; &ldquo;Belt&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>My thumb is where I was at in January. I need to buy some new pants.</p>

<p>January: <strong>220.0</strong></p>

<p>(September) Week 1 &ndash; Day 1: <strong>185.0</strong></p>

<p>Week 1 &ndash; Day 1: <strong>185.0</strong></p>

<p>Week 2 &ndash; Day 8: <strong>179.8</strong></p>

<p>Week 3 &ndash; Day 15: <strong>178.2</strong></p>

<p>Week 4 &ndash; Day 22: <strong>173.8</strong></p>

<p>Week 5 &ndash; Day 29: <strong>171.0</strong></p>

<p>Week 6 &ndash; Day 36: <strong>166.6</strong></p>

<p>Week 7 &ndash; Day 43: <strong>164.5</strong></p>

<p>Week 8 &ndash; Day 50: <strong>162.0</strong></p>

<p>Week 9 &ndash; Day 57: <strong>161.0 (Traveling, weighed in on day 54)</strong></p>

<p>Current total transformation loss: <strong>24.0</strong></p>

<p>Current total loss: <strong>59.0</strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/2014-10-28-progress-update-the-weeks-ive-missed/cassette_shirt.jpg" title="&ldquo;Cassette Shirt&rdquo; &ldquo;Cassette Shirt&rdquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Update - Week 2 and 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/09/22/progress-update-week-2-and-3/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-22T20:54:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/09/22/progress-update-week-2-and-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Week 2 Weigh In</h3>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a picture of me dying. I have the coolest t-shirts.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2014-09-22-progress-update-week-2-and-3/im_dying.jpg" title="&ldquo;I&rsquo;m dying&rdquo; &ldquo;I&rsquo;m dying&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Week 1 &ndash; Day 1: <strong>185.0</strong></p>

<p>Week 2 &ndash; Day 8: <strong>179.8</strong></p>

<p>Week 3 &ndash; Day 15: <strong>178.2</strong></p>

<p>Current total loss: <strong>6.8</strong></p>

<p>Last week, I did not lose much weight at all &ndash;<strong>1.6 pounds.</strong> Even though progress should not be as large as week 1, there still should have been more then that. There are several reason for this:</p>

<h4>No week should have the same progress as week 1</h4>

<h4>My diet needs to change</h4>

<p>I need to cut some of the carbs out of my diet. I&rsquo;m consuming a lot more then I should. Instead of having 1 cup of pasta/rice, it&rsquo;s being cut down to 2/3.</p>

<h4>I had a cheat day (A day to eat myself silly!)</h4>

<p>Ain&rsquo;t she purty!?
<img src="/images/2014-09-22-progress-update-week-2-and-3/me_and_jenny.jpg" title="&ldquo;Me and Jenny&rdquo; &ldquo;Me and Jenny&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>Jenny&rsquo;s, Brian&rsquo;s, and Shannon&rsquo;s (Brian&rsquo;s lady) birthdays are all in September, so we had a big birthday bash on Saturday. I ate myself silly. Hot dogs, burgers, doughnuts, cake &ndash; so much sugar I made myself sick. This was for a reason. Even though this cheat day was planned, I wanted to stop all of these cravings I was having, so I ate the foods my body was craving until I got sick. And that&rsquo;s OK. Now, I ain&rsquo;t cravin' shit!</p>

<p>Cravings were not a huge problem the second week. I am on autopilot now.</p>

<hr>


<h3>Week 3 Weigh In</h3>

<p>Week 1 &ndash; Day 1: <strong>185.0</strong></p>

<p>Week 2 &ndash; Day 8: <strong>179.8</strong></p>

<p>Week 3 &ndash; Day 15: <strong>178.2</strong></p>

<p>Week 4 &ndash; Day 22: <strong>173.8</strong></p>

<p>Current total loss: <strong>11.2</strong></p>

<p>HUGE week!! <strong>4.4 pounds</strong> lost! Last week was ROUGH. My body is having trouble adjusting to the changes in diet and it&rsquo;s not taking it well. Kris Gethin warned this would happen, but it&rsquo;s hard to prepare for it. I&rsquo;m extremely irritable and can&rsquo;t focus as well as normal. The lack of fat sucks.</p>

<p>The irritability issues lasted a few days. No big deal. I&rsquo;m still having issues focusing like I used to, but it&rsquo;s getting better!</p>

<p>I also ran the &ldquo;Run or Dye&rdquo; 5k on September 20th! It was a ton of fun &ndash; everyone has bags of dye and runs a few miles while throwing the dye on other people. I was all kinds of green/yellow/purple/pink while going to the gym later for my 2nd cardio session.</p>

<p>Me and Brian posing at the start
<img src="/images/2014-09-22-progress-update-week-2-and-3/start.jpg" title="&ldquo;Me and Brian&rdquo; &ldquo;Me and Brian&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>I lost Brian.
<img src="/images/2014-09-22-progress-update-week-2-and-3/finish.jpg" title="&ldquo;Where did Brian go?&rdquo; &ldquo;Where did Brian go?&rdquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First VLog! Week 2 - Day 12]]></title>
    <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/09/22/my-first-vlog/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-22T20:41:42-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/09/22/my-first-vlog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lWZ4sgRFqoo"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/lWZ4sgRFqoo/0.jpg" alt="Week 2 - Day 12" /></a></p>

<p>I am not a good writer, nor am I good in front of a camera. So why not practice both by blogging more, and vlogging more? Day 12 of my body transformation is a decent place to start, eh?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
