<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life Balance | Nick Bucciarelli]]></title>
  <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/categories/life-balance/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-16T16:26:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Bucciarelli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maintaining Good Balance]]></title>
    <link href="http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/04/11/maintaining-good-balance/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-11T10:51:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://nbucciarelli.github.io/blog/2014/04/11/maintaining-good-balance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Programming is awesome, hands down. I can sit down on a couch, on a beach in lovely Charleston, or on a mountain. I can do it from anywhere and have my ideas come directly from my head onto a web browser. It&rsquo;s crazy!</p>

<p>When I was first introduced to this, I would sit down for DAYS and just learn and write code. Granted, the code was really bad, but I was on the way to becoming successful! My schedule would be this:</p>

<ul>
<li>Wake up</li>
<li>Turn on computer</li>
<li>Learn some stuff</li>
<li>Repeat for 16 hours</li>
<li>Eat dinner</li>
<li>Go to sleep</li>
</ul>


<p>Does anyone see what&rsquo;s wrong with this? This is the same stuff I would do every day. I let myself lead an extremely unhealthy, sedentary lifestyle. Although happy and successful, I was letting my health spiral out of control. My weight went up; I was getting fat and I didn&rsquo;t care.</p>

<p>Too much of a good thing isn&rsquo;t good for you! You need to maintain a good balance between sitting and moving or you will have severe consequences later in life! Thankfully I caught these issues before they got too severe.</p>

<h3>Tips</h3>

<p>While developing, you need to take breaks. Start simple. 2 hours on, 15 minutes off. During those 15 minutes, make sure you&rsquo;re moving around. Do some pushups, do some pullups, do some crunches, go walk a brisk half-mile. Do something! Get moving!</p>

<p>You don&rsquo;t have to be pumping iron every day, but you don&rsquo;t want to sit on your ass all day every day either. Maintain a balance!</p>

<p>Maintaining a good balance is not just about working out/getting up and moving. You need to properly separate your work and play. Give developing a rest! Have pre-defined cut-off points where if you aren&rsquo;t finished your assignment, get the hell off the computer. You need to have defined separation between work and play. Play can&rsquo;t be you going from one computer developing to another doing research. Spend time with your friends or family.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t hesitate to tell someone that you can&rsquo;t create their website if you&rsquo;re already booked. Do not book contracts during your free time. There are always exceptions, but if there is no need, don&rsquo;t do it!</p>

<p>Maintaining a proper balance is crucial to being successful. Personal relationships and your health are just as important (maybe even more so?) as your work. It will make you a well-rounded developer and a much more likeable person.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
